[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339219", "question": "What actor is known as \"The Fonz\"?", "answer": "Henry Winkler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9d", "question": "What color is the square that's the logo for H&R Block?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aff", "question": "Which character killed Jay Gatsby?", "answer": "George Wilson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5e", "question": "Which book of the Bible recounts the story of Noah and the Ark?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4e", "question": "New York's Wall Street was named when a wall was built there for what purpose?", "answer": "Defense from attack", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a50d", "question": "On which island is the Empire State Building located?", "answer": "Manhattan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a1e1dd1b5a031299b74573d", "question": "What century did the Icelandic Vikings first reach the island of Newfoundland?", "answer": "11th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339045", "question": "What artist composed the opera \"Tannhauser\"?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2b", "question": "Who wrote \"De Profundis\" while in prison?", "answer": "Oscar Wilde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3d0124f032c0db195b496", "question": "For what crime was Margaret Sanger jailed in 1917?", "answer": "Establishing birth control", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec23ce8dc25ca9e12ef633", "question": "What don't the children need in Pink Floyd's \"Another Brick In The Wall\"?", "answer": "An education", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34f", "question": "What shape is the body of an Erlenmeyer flask?", "answer": "Conical", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f5dd01dd7bf43be5e82c", "question": "What surface are Wimbledon tennis matches played on?", "answer": "Grass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d80", "question": "What ABC TV star is the great-grandson of a billionaire oilman?", "answer": "Balthazar Getty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ee", "question": "Who played the role of Daniel in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Ralph Macchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda1", "question": "What are the \"ten\" referred to when a surfer \"hangs ten\" on a wave?", "answer": "His ten toes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a03", "question": "Who wrote \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Dan Brown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5c", "question": "What is the capital of Rwanda?", "answer": "Kigali", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925b", "question": "What hit song plays on the radio alarm clock in the movie \"Groundhog Day\"?", "answer": "I Got You Babe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec24c58dc25ca9e12ef63a", "question": "What was the very first Andrew Lloyd Webber musical to be adapted to film?", "answer": "Jesus Christ Superstar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95f", "question": "Which numbers are either side of the number sixteen on a dart board?", "answer": "7 and 8", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e8032fde59ea584496fe9b", "question": "In which 1949 film does Alec Guinness portray nine members of the D'Ascoyne family?", "answer": "Kind Hearts and Coronets", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bbedd96d05b23b281651", "question": "The Peloponnesian War was fought between Athens and which other ancient Greek state?", "answer": "Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b818", "question": "What did my true love give to me on the fifth day of Christmas?", "answer": "Five golden rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fc", "question": "What was Hawaii's main agricultural crop during the first half of the 20th century?", "answer": "Sugarcane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c258", "question": "In the computer world, what does the abbreviation CPU stand for?", "answer": "Central Processing Unit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a2", "question": "Who was the first man to return safely from space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b678", "question": "A \"top-sider\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c35aa815febcc896f925f", "question": "In which country would you most likely find the traditional Mariachi bands?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65f031f3c0ead6880d633", "question": "Which kind of bulbs were once exchanged as a form of currency?", "answer": "Tulips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdd5eca0499cffc60b84235", "question": "What did a shepherd boy discover at Qumran, Jordan, in 1946 and 1947?", "answer": "Dead Sea Scrolls", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d55", "question": "Emilio Estevez was originally cast in what other actor's role in \"The Breakfast Club\"?", "answer": "Judd Nelson's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389fc", "question": "What title role was filled by Lon Chaney in 1923, Charles Laughton in 1939 and Anthony Hopkins in 1982?", "answer": "The Hunchback of Notre Dame", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd660f8a5bfecdd737e0839", "question": "Where did the tradition of pumpkin carving originate?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b144", "question": "Who did Muhammad Ali defeat to gain the World Heavyweight boxing title for the first time?", "answer": "Sonny Liston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b192", "question": "What year did Napoleon Bonaparte die?", "answer": "1821", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfb3d9dc5ec6cd98a8315", "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a845", "question": "What Florida city is known as the \"Winter Strawberry Capital of the World\"?", "answer": "Plant City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b156", "question": "How old was Lady Diana when she married Prince Charles?", "answer": "20", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb60d05dad637d903c882c", "question": "The Rungnado 1st of May Stadium, built in honor of the May Day holiday, exists in which country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf80", "question": "What is a tightrope walker called?", "answer": "Funambulist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd4a5200d154d7af00b8cc", "question": "Which artist founded the record label \"Aftermath Entertainment\"?", "answer": "Dr. Dre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c6749076251badbead3", "question": "In the U.S., the 1920s were often described by what term?", "answer": "The roaring twenties ", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc1d7ec223966ae8f886e", "question": "The \"Tina\" in Tina Fey is short for what name?", "answer": "Stamatina", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c889", "question": "What is the chemical name for a dentist's \"laughing gas\"?", "answer": "Nitrous oxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78c", "question": "Grits are typically made from what grain?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf09", "question": "In which gymnastics discipline would a man do the scissors?", "answer": "Pommel Horse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58be2d038faf425cf37add7a", "question": "In Greek mythology, which of the nine Muses is normally depicted sitting down and holding a lyre?", "answer": "Terpsichore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd668d1a5bfecdd737e0873", "question": "What was the name of the Beatles' first studio album?", "answer": "Cargo House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b57b", "question": "What nationality was Pope John Paul II?", "answer": "Polish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393aa", "question": "What movie was Sean Penn's directorial debut?", "answer": "Indian Runner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c0", "question": "Who played the role of Kenneth Parcell on the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "Jack McBrayer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f76", "question": "Which Shakespearean character has the most lines?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e5", "question": "The Caribbean island of Aruba is part of what European kingdom?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339923", "question": "What was the name of the high school in the movie \u201cGrease\u201d?", "answer": "Rydell High", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc87", "question": "What's the \"safest\" color on the US Homeland Security Advisory System's color scale?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc5", "question": "Ditra Flame was the \"Lady in Black\" who took thirteen red roses to what actor's grave every year?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6d", "question": "What are the names of the four Musketeers?", "answer": "Athos, Aramis, Porthos and D\u2019artagnan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c9ef0775fa611bce67f0", "question": "What breed of dog was used to popularize the phrase \"Yo quiero Taco Bell\"?", "answer": "Chihuahua -- Gidget, the 8-pound female Chihuahua, was only Taco Bell\u2019s mascot for 3 years, but she made the most of her time.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb60665ff7d326b622a93", "question": "Under what title was Agatha Christie's \"Murder on the Orient Express\" first published in the US?", "answer": "Murder on the Calais Coach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd40", "question": "Who has been the pole sitter at a record six Indy 500s, from 1979 to 1991?", "answer": "Rick Mears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985c", "question": "In the movie \"Howl's Moving Castle\", Calcifer was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f025cee580c7f8fd1e4a", "question": "What famous general was nicknamed \"Old blood and guts\" by his men?", "answer": "General George S. Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25a53b63e5727cf5a4852", "question": "Who sang the songs \"Bump n' Grind\" and \"She's Got That Vibe\"?", "answer": "R Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4b", "question": "What is Ralph Lauren's real last name?", "answer": "Lifschitz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0d", "question": "In the Tom Petty song \"Free Fallin'\", the girl is a big fan of what singer?", "answer": "Elvis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078566bd51d85e222ab65e", "question": "Who said: \"I\u2019m the president of the United States, and I\u2019m not going to eat any more broccoli\"?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush (He once made a joke that the workers in the Office of Personnel Management would get merit pay \"in broccoli\").", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339900", "question": "What was Clair Huxtable's profession on \"The Cosby Show\"?", "answer": "Lawyer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5a", "question": "Who was Germany's first female chancellor?", "answer": "Angela Merkel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03e", "question": "Brian, Stewie and whom make up \"The New Rat Pack\" on the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra, Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab96c786faa38a764be523", "question": "Which car company did Christian von Koenigsegg found in 1994?", "answer": "Koenigsegg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4ac949076251badbeabc", "question": "Which amendment to the U.S. Constitution granted Black men the right to vote?", "answer": "In 1870, the U.S. Congress passed the 15th Amendment\u2014 seven years after the Emancipation Proclamation.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cb7dbb53d1af658864d8", "question": "What band released a single in 1977 entitled \"Father Christmas\"?", "answer": "The Kinks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945a", "question": "Who does Eddie Murphy trade places with in the 1983 movie \"Trading Places\"?", "answer": "Dan Aykroyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908a", "question": "What well known Russian author was also a doctor?", "answer": "Anton Chekhov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7b", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The African Queen\" set?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f3eeaaf848b908361b86a", "question": "What country's flag features a trident?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e2d506d333868d34d72a", "question": "What is the United States Bill of Rights?", "answer": "The first ten amendments to the U.S. Constitution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f6", "question": "What is the full name of writer H. G. Wells?", "answer": "Herbert George Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d5", "question": "Which South American country takes its name from Christopher Columbus?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4dc", "question": "What two alcoholic ingredients is the traditional Martini cocktail made of?", "answer": "Gin and vermouth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb6", "question": "In the nursery rhyme \"The Cat and the Fiddle\", what runs away with the spoon?", "answer": "The dish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ae", "question": "Who received a patent for the first electric razor in 1930?", "answer": "Jacob Schick", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f7", "question": "Libreville is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Gabon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25f2066682715b82711ce6", "question": "Feijoada is the national dish of which South American country?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b3724d1c3f17ccc40c8e23", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd05", "question": "After his death in a 1998 skiing accident, what famous song title was placed on Sonny Bono's headstone?", "answer": "The Beat Goes On", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c4", "question": "Which star of \"Cheers\" also starred in the TV show \"Veronica's Closet\"?", "answer": "Kirstie Alley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe657aeae7e414034b5aee0", "question": "In the Bible, who took over Belshazzar's empire?", "answer": "Darius", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a112", "question": "\"Dance with a Stranger\" was the film of who's life story?", "answer": "Ruth Ellis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c817", "question": "What would a doctor call \"pes planus\"?", "answer": "Fallen arches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6606aa5bfecdd737e0833", "question": "In which state are two-thirds of all Fortune 500 companies headquartered?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b0", "question": "What nation was led by Sargon the Great?", "answer": "Akkad", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601601b0fe83fe1f2a824c61", "question": "Many countries do not forthrightly recognize May Day but celebrate which other holiday in its stead?", "answer": "International Workers Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff25a8431a458464a93c472", "question": "Which condiment is traditionally served with fried seafood in the United States?", "answer": "Tartar Sauce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93c", "question": "The phrase \"banana republic\" was first coined by O. Henry in reference to what country?", "answer": "Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6016009afe83fe1f2a824c56", "question": "What was the subject of the first color photograph?", "answer": "A tartan ribbon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b6", "question": "In a 6-string, ordinarily tuned guitar, what are the 6 open notes?", "answer": "EADGBE", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fbae3fc0738315b1fb74e1d", "question": "Who won Chelsea's Player of the Year in 2012 and 2013?", "answer": "Juan Mata", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b0", "question": "Balsam, Fraser, and Douglas are all types of what?", "answer": "Firs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d1", "question": "The song \"A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes\" was originally featured in what Disney film?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162c2ef01ec323f849172e", "question": "Who was the legendary front man for the band Roxy Music?", "answer": "Bryan Ferry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff212f831a458464a93c44c", "question": "What is name of the holiday also celebrated on February 14, yet dedicated to recognizing singles?", "answer": "Quirkyalone Day (Observers are advised to celebrate platonic, familial and self love in addition to romance on February 14)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ea", "question": "In what bay would you find the Andaman and Nicobar islands?", "answer": "The Bay of Bengal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b973", "question": "Which Scotland Yard detective lead the hunt for Ronnie Biggs in the sixties?", "answer": "Jack Slipper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c096", "question": "In what sport do teams compete for the Swaythling Cup?", "answer": "Table tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22b", "question": "Gandhi's famous march to Dandi in 1930 was an act to protest against Great Britain's tax on what?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e21", "question": "Which character was most seriously injured by the winged monkeys in the film \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "The Scarecrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed1", "question": "What reality show gave America the catchphrase \"That's hot\"?", "answer": "The Simple Life", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049c00cf93664eb10486a3", "question": "Art Spiegelman is best known for his creation of which graphic novel?", "answer": "Maus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febbc8b7e83c707845b214d", "question": "In what round of the NFL draft was quarterback Tom Brady selected in?", "answer": "Brady was the 199th pick in the sixth round of the 2000 NFL draft.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cee", "question": "What artist performed the song titled \"MMMBop\"?", "answer": "Hanson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62f", "question": "Long-period comets are believed to come from where?", "answer": "The Oort Cloud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea31b7ff048f679a45aae3", "question": "What type of rock is obsidian?", "answer": "Igneous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f4d9fa5fdd6dd25324e7", "question": "Central African Republic shares its western border with which country?", "answer": "Cameroon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e803f7de59ea584496fea1", "question": "The novel \"The Starlight Barking\" is the sequel to which popular children's book?", "answer": "The Hundred and One Dalmatians", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b692", "question": "Klaxon horns were used on what type of vehicle during World War II?", "answer": "Submarines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58a0f5ea732c90c4fd3069cf", "question": "Who was the childhood playmate of little Jackie Papers?", "answer": "Puff, the Magic Dragon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eaff9f83302ff91e46497", "question": "Jimmy Connors won the men's doubles at the 1973 Wimbledon with which partner?", "answer": "Ilie Nastase", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0f", "question": "Who was the only woman to hold the title office in the \"Book of Judges\"?", "answer": "Deborah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ea81b24f84e0b9f9ffd5", "question": "Homichlophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fog or humidity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b9", "question": "What was Peter Gunn's girlfriend's name?", "answer": "Edie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b4b0eee65b76b9f2666", "question": "In which country did the Easter Rising take place in 1916?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a819", "question": "What river divides the city of Budapest into the \"districts\" of Buda and Pest?", "answer": "The Danube", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a62742ebb971c1417fb8f", "question": "In which Olympic games did Nadia Com\u0103neci become the first gymnist to be awarded a perfect score of 10.0?", "answer": "1976 Olympic Games", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a988", "question": "What city named its airport after John Foster Dulles?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3cc", "question": "Due to getting sick, which astronaut was replaced in the Apollo XIII mission?", "answer": "Ken Mattingly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4d971908b8581f80b092a8", "question": "What country was host to the \u201c2017 World Expo\u201d?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59c", "question": "Who was the first deaf Miss America, crowned in 1995?", "answer": "Heather Whitestone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a62972ebb971c1417fb90", "question": "What fish was the subject of a dispute between Spain and Canada from 1994 to 1996?", "answer": "Turbot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2d", "question": "Newton divided the visible spectrum into which seven colors?", "answer": "Red, orange, yellow, green, blue, indigo and violet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396af", "question": "What actor founded the Purple Rose Theater Company in Michigan?", "answer": "Jeff Daniels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95d", "question": "What is the first prime number that comes after 100?", "answer": "101", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede5006ce05a3942286de4", "question": "What were George Harrison's names in the Traveling Wilburys?", "answer": "Nelson and Spike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aece", "question": "What was the second successful mass produced car by the Ford Motor Company called?", "answer": "Model A", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade6", "question": "What was Che Guevara's real first name?", "answer": "Ernesto", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338968", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was arachnophobic?", "answer": "Little Miss Muffet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b57181f67df192a942e335b", "question": "What kind of creature was Sam on \"The Muppet Show\"?", "answer": "Eagle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b32d01dd7bf43be5e7a9", "question": "What did Prince Harry use as his last name while serving in the military?", "answer": "Wales", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a91", "question": "Where did the Yellow Brick Road lead to?", "answer": "Emerald City", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd1", "question": "What TV show did \"Mork and Mindy\" spin off from?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c435", "question": "What is the only bone in the human body that doesn't connect with any other?", "answer": "Hyoid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339620", "question": "What movie earned Francis Ford Coppola a Palme d'Or in 1979?", "answer": "Apocalypse Now", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636c30967692ea851899a8", "question": "Which \"Committee of Five\" member was the 2nd President of the United States?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd6", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"guitar\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a82", "question": "What female dog is the secret object of Underdog\u2019s affection?", "answer": "Sweet Polly Purebred", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d6", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Marble Man\"?", "answer": "Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b400", "question": "What was Alaska called before 1867?", "answer": "Russian America", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb0ce7e83c707845b2108", "question": "What insect protects peonies from damaging pests?", "answer": "Ants", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85d", "question": "What is the World's 9th largest country by land area?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20c", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ff", "question": "Which character does Kevin Spacey play in the 1995 movie \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Roger Kint/Keyser Soze", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe733a8eec85e375820b223", "question": "In a Nazi concentration camp, a black triangle identified a prisoner as what?", "answer": "Asocial", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdaffe65ff7d326b622a5e", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b193", "question": "What year did Napoleon become the Emperor of the French?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40f", "question": "Brown University is located in which US state?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597ddf2077980686f722d183", "question": "What year was the first official Association football game played?", "answer": "1863", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfea99dc5ec6cd98a832b", "question": "What word did Robert A. Heinlein introduce into the English language in his book \"Stranger in a Strange Land\"?", "answer": "In the 1961 science-fiction novel, Heinlein coined the term Grok, which means \"to understand intuitively or by empathy\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7e", "question": "Who played Lex Luthor in the 2006 film \"Superman Returns\"?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9444574a5ce6b56b8247", "question": "What was Agatha Christie's second husband's profession?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f8", "question": "What is the process of splitting atoms called?", "answer": "Fission", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb2a265ff7d326b622a76", "question": "What is the fear of mushrooms known as?", "answer": "Mycophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac8", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Montana?", "answer": "Helena", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071dcc3745b36be73039dd", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4f", "question": "What country music artist was married briefly to actress Renee Zellweger?", "answer": "Kenny Chesney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f48b3af848b908361b879", "question": "How many people made up the US Electoral College in 2020?", "answer": "538", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa97", "question": "What ocean does the Zambezi River empty into?", "answer": "Indian ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5906823cff9c0647b50a809b", "question": "Which NFL team won Super Bowl 50?", "answer": "Denver Broncos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fb", "question": "Who was the first Canadian-born boxer to win the heavyweight championship?", "answer": "Tommy Burns", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a8", "question": "What is the middle color in a rainbow?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339335", "question": "What actress played JR's wife on Dallas?", "answer": "Linda Gray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc10d6ce05a3942286f0d", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Private Eyes\"?", "answer": "Hall and Oates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017378544491cbd7c5a178b", "question": "How did the U.S. state Tennessee aquire the nickname, \"The Volunteer State\"?", "answer": "It became known as \"The Volunteer State\" during the War of 1812 due to its prominent role of sending 1,500 volunteer soldiers.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b220", "question": "What city was Billy Clanton killed in?", "answer": "Tombstone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd417bac329055bc655127b", "question": "Where were U.S. coins with the letters \"CC\" on them minted?", "answer": "Carson City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe93b5c6bd93ce3a4e5f6a3", "question": "What did Evangelista Torricelli invent?", "answer": "Mercury barometer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa2", "question": "The first album by the Velvet Underground featured what fruit on the cover?", "answer": "A banana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cac", "question": "Who replaced Stanley Kubrick on the western film \"One-Eyed Jacks\", making it the only film he ever directed?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c963", "question": "Parr, Smolt and Grilse are lifecycle stages for what fish?", "answer": "Salmon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3234debf195a31e15d73a9", "question": "Who played Derek Flint in the 1966 film \"Our Man Flint\"?", "answer": "James Coburn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe767f8eec85e375820b29c", "question": "Which city is considered the birthplace of democracy?", "answer": "Athens, Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392cf", "question": "What film stars Bruce Willis as a plastic surgeon Ernest Menville?", "answer": "Death Becomes Her", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61e", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Titanium?", "answer": "Ti", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f49801dd7bf43be5e824", "question": "Where does Sherry wine come from?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ef", "question": "In the movie \"Carrie\", what type of blood was she covered in?", "answer": "Pig's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66b1e52a821ff76ae8b0c", "question": "People who scavenged the sewers of London during the Victoria era were called what?", "answer": "Tosher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f28", "question": "\"The Great White Hope\" is a fictionalized account of what first black heavyweight champ?", "answer": "Jack Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0e86c964118b2bb3809c5", "question": "In Slovenia, Saint Valentine is considered the saint of good health and the patron of whom?", "answer": "Beekeepers and pilgrims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ed", "question": "Shakespeare mentioned his wife only once in his will, making her the odd bequest of his \"second best\" what?", "answer": "Bed", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea45dcff048f679a45ab9a", "question": "What is a Canis Lupus?", "answer": "Gray Wolf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd6", "question": "According to legend, what outlaw killed one man for each of the 21 years he lived?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012185b63c99d48cd169af1", "question": "The first hockey pucks used in early outdoor hockey games were made of what?", "answer": "Frozen cow dung", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b66e", "question": "What does the CN stand for in the CN Tower?", "answer": "Canadian National", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66e", "question": "Which have longer snouts - alligators or crocodiles?", "answer": "Crocodiles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04a", "question": "Gene, Louise, Tina, Bob, and Linda are the main characters of which animated sitcom?", "answer": "Bob's Burgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18e", "question": "What year was Stonehenge added to UNESCO's list of World Heritage sites?", "answer": "1986", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eae8cf83302ff91e4648a", "question": "What animal is a Chester White?", "answer": "A pig", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a285", "question": "Which Mike Judge-directed comedy featured the characters Peter Gibbons and Michael Bolton?", "answer": "Office Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c7", "question": "In the game \"Plants vs Zombies\", what do players collect as currency to buy plants?", "answer": "Sunlight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e54", "question": "What literary work inspired Led Zeppelin's \"The Battle of Evermore\" song?", "answer": "The Lord of the Rings", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ec2b15043630d44e5be228d", "question": "Who started the vision for the long-established fashion for the Kentucky Derby races?", "answer": "Col. Meriwether Lewis Clark Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339640", "question": "Oswald Cobblepot is better known as who?", "answer": "The Penguin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e3", "question": "Mary Lou Retton won five medals in what sport at the 1984 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Gymnastics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69ae020565ad31a57c757", "question": "What was the first non-axis jet plane to see combat?", "answer": "Gloster Meteor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339244", "question": "What movie was hyped: \"Girls like me don't make invitations like this to just anyone\"?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a07", "question": "Which Shakespeare play sees the brother of a novice nun sentenced to death for fornication?", "answer": "Measure for Measure", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d7", "question": "Which is US's largest state by land area?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f0", "question": "The first Rolling Stones song to hit the British Top 20 was a rendition of what Lennon-McCartney song?", "answer": "I Wanna Be Your Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a94e661d1b4d384d5d673", "question": "Elzie Segar created what popular character?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a92", "question": "What is the station and platform number for the Hogwarts Express?", "answer": "King's Cross Station, Platform 9 3/4", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339250", "question": "What Stanley Kubrick movie was hyped: \"In Vietnam the wind doesn't blow, it sucks\"?", "answer": "Full Metal Jacket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba00", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Honus Wagner play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fe", "question": "What compound makes up around 60% of the human body weight?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede0e66ce05a3942286dbd", "question": "In the film \"Schindler's List\" what city was the setting?", "answer": "Krakow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901db26709c1c34536e6eb1", "question": "In what sport would a contestant perform a \"Fosberry Flop\"?", "answer": "High jump", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8cc", "question": "Burning potassium has what color flame?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ae862267f28483af1e7fdc6", "question": "Who was the author of the novel \"War and Peace\"?", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b786", "question": "What is an \"Americano\"?", "answer": "Espresso with hot water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be02", "question": "What is another name for a \"numismatist\"?", "answer": "Coin collector", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc91", "question": "What is the \"waltzing Matilda\" in the title of that traditional Australian song?", "answer": "A migrant worker's bedroll", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9bbe5364247bf200fb8aa", "question": "What country borders Zambia to the west?", "answer": "Angola", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e940c7ccba3ffe45786cd", "question": "What year did Buddy Holly die in a plane crash?", "answer": "1959", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0cc", "question": "What general led the Mexicans in the siege against the Alamo?", "answer": "Santa Ana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad6", "question": "In 1996, what became the first minivan to be named Motor Trend magazine's \"Car of the Year\"?", "answer": "Dodge Caravan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b30e", "question": "What team won the 100th anniversary Stanley Cup?", "answer": "The Montreal Canadiens", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f4684af848b908361b876", "question": "As of 2020, what is the highest grossing film of all time without taking inflation into account?", "answer": "Avengers: Endgame", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c157", "question": "Which three ingredients does a Kamikaze cocktail contain?", "answer": "Vodka, triple sec and lime juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febba487e83c707845b2144", "question": "The Philadelphia Flyers of the 1970's were known as the \"Broad Street\" what?", "answer": "Bullies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d7a02596a59cbdfbd3b8", "question": "Martha Jane Canary was a sharpshooting frontierswoman better known as?", "answer": "Calamity Jane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb3", "question": "What Big US East school took the cryptic name for its sports teams from the Greek word for \"what\"?", "answer": "Georgetown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc080ec223966ae8f885b", "question": "Which actor made his film debut in \"Back to the Future\" as one of Biff's cronies?", "answer": "Billy Zane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a176", "question": "Who directed the film \"The Bridge on the River Kwai\"?", "answer": "David Lean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb61505dad637d903c882f", "question": "In 2014, a criminal gang in China used the chemical rongalite to flood the market with which contaminated food?", "answer": "Tofu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde5129c6c6b019850c9a8d", "question": "Who was the first King of the Northern Ten Tribes of Israel during the time of the Divided Kingdom?", "answer": "Jeroboam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb07", "question": "In physics, what does FTL stand for?", "answer": "Faster than light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc0", "question": "What is the name of the production company founded by Oprah Winfrey in 1986?", "answer": "Harpo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13c", "question": "With which group is Damon Albarn the lead singer?", "answer": "Blur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339700", "question": "Who replaced David Tennant to become the doctor in \"Doctor Who\"?", "answer": "Matt Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b65ae662d71a53651006", "question": "Who played Anita in the first Broadway production of West Side Story?", "answer": "Chita Rivera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59636c6c967692ea851899ab", "question": "What popular destination helped popularize hot dogs in the US in the 19th century?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339895", "question": "The line \"Greed, for a lack of better word, is good!\" can be heard in what movie?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd6a37e83c707845b216b", "question": "Which actor committed himself to solitary confinement in order to prepare for his role in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62e", "question": "How many planets in our Solar System have moons?", "answer": "6", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6c", "question": "What comic strip character\u2019s favorite baseball player was Joe Shlabotnik?", "answer": "Charlie Brown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65d511f3c0ead6880d61a", "question": "The Haloid Company is the original name of what company?", "answer": "Xerox", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba4", "question": "Which state is located between Wisconsin and North Dakota?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ed", "question": "Into which bay does the Golden Gate Strait lead?", "answer": "San Francisco Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f4", "question": "In the Disney movie \"Robin Hood\", what animals play Robin Hood and Maid Marian?", "answer": "Foxes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121c2b63c99d48cd169b12", "question": "Norman Rockwell painted 323 covers for which magazine?", "answer": "\"Saturday Evening Post\" -- The magazine featured Rockwell\u2019s work from 1916 to 1963.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a87620565ad31a57c7f5", "question": "Which U.S. state ignored Prohibition?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b436", "question": "Which Italian city was severely damaged by an earthquake in 1908?", "answer": "Messina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14722b0ee8c595b6d39c3", "question": "What was Sleeping Beauty poisoned by?", "answer": "A spindle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d117d64fea7fe947a2227e", "question": "Which German firm produced the World War II plane known as the Condor?", "answer": "Focke-Wulf", "category": "science"}]